Guide to the Echols Collection records, 1952-2000.
Echols Collection records, 1952-2000.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Echols Collection records, 1952-2000.
13-6-1973
Cornell University.Library.John M. Echols Collection on Southeast Asia.
42 cubic ft.
Correspondence, serials files
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence relating to the administration of the Echols Collection. Also, Southeast Asia serials files.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence relating to the administration of the Echols Collection. Also, Southeast Asia serials files.
Two letters to Cornell University Library from Buri Navarast, the Siamese Minister at the Siamese Legation in Washington, D.C.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Navarast, Buri.; Cornell University--Libraries.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to permission of office of origin.
PROVENANCE
The letterbooks and correspondence of the Jacob Gould Schurman papers derive from the Office of the President of Cornell University, and for many years were in the care of Cornell University Library. Other correspondence, photographs, testimonials and social correspondence, and personal and family letters were transferred to the Department of Manuscripts and University Archives at various times from Schurman family members, notably including Judge Jacob G. Schurman, Lydia Schurman Godfrey, and G. Michael McHugh. Some Schurman letters have on several occasions over the years been transferred from the Department of Rare Books of Cornell University Library. Other contributors have included John R. Silber, and the Dewitt Historical Society of Ithaca, New York.
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a partial finding aid for Boxes 1-11.
  Not all the material in the collection is covered by this guide.
- Burma, 1994-2002 (Box 47, Folder 1)
- Burma: Mandalay Book Agency, 1993-1997 (Box 47, Folder 2)
- Cambodia I, 1998-2002 (Box 47, Folder 3)
- Cambodia II, 1993-1997 (Box 47, Folder 4)
- Cambodia III, 1994-1996 (Box 47, Folder 5)
- Cambodia IV, 1992-1994 (Box 47, Folder 6)
- Cambodia, 1993-1994 (Box 47, Folder 7)
- Cambodia, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 8)
- Cambodia, 1996-2002 (Box 47, Folder 9)
- Conservation/Preservation, 1991; 1994 (Box 47, Folder 10)
- CORMOSEA ARL, 1996-1997 (Box 47, Folder 11)
- CORMOSEA/Luce, 1989-1993 (Box 47, Folder 12)
- East Timor, 1993-1998 (Box 47, Folder 13)
- Indonesia, 1994-1999 (Box 47, Folder 14)
- Indonesia: Library of Congress Field Office Southeast Asia, 1990-1992 (Box 47, Folder 15)
- Laos I, II, 1999-2000 (Box 47, Folder 16-17)
- Laos III, 1997-1999 (Box 47, Folder 18)
- Laos, 1997-2001 (Box 47, Folder 19)
- Malaysia, 1988-1995 (Box 47, Folder 20)
- Malaysia, 1993-1999 (Box 47, Folder 21)
- Philippines, 1980-1996 (Box 47, Folder 22)
- Philippines, 1992-1996 (Box 47, Folder 23)
- Philippines, 1993-1999 (Box 47, Folder 24)
- Philippines: Marcos' victims transcripts, 1997 (Box 47, Folder 25)
- Singapore, 1993-1995 (Box 47, Folder 26)
- Southeast Asia, 1994-1995 (Box 47, Folder 27)
- Thailand, 1991-1994 (Box 47, Folder 28)
- Thailand I, 1997-2000 (Box 47, Folder 29)
- Thailand II, 1996-1997 (Box 47, Folder 30)
- Thailand III, 1994-1996 (Box 47, Folder 31)
- Thailand IV, 1992-2000 (Box 47, Folder 32)
- Thailand/Laos, 1992-1997 (Box 47, Folder 33)
- [Thailand] Nibondh prices, 1997-1998 (Box 47, Folder 34)
- Vietnam, 1993-2000 (Box 47, Folder 35)
- [Vietnam] Xunhasaba, 1993-2003 (Box 47, Folder 36)
- Anthropology Asia Collections, 1993-1996 (Box 48, Folder 1)
- Asia Collections, 1992-1996 (Box 48, Folder 2)
- Asia Library Services, 1991-1996 (Box 48, Folder 3)
- Audio-visual, 1990-1991 (Box 48, Folder 4)
- BAS (Bibliography of Asian Studies), 1993-1996 (Box 48, Folder 5-6)
- Breezewood Collection, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 7)
- Burma Cultural Preservation -USIA Project, 1993-1994 (Box 48, Folder 8)
- Burmese photo collection, 1981-1991 (Box 48, Folder 9)
- Cambodia, Tuol Sleng, Chris Riley, 1994-1996 (Box 48, Folder 10)
- Chines language publications, special allocation, 1994-1995 (Box 48, Folder 11)
- CORMOSEA, 1995 (Box 48, Folder 12)
- CORMOSEA, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 13)
- CORMOSEA, 1997 (Box 48, Folder 14)
- CORMOSEA, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 15)
- CORMOSEA, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 16)
- CORMOSEA - financial, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 17)
- CORMOSEA, 2000 (Box 48, Folder 18)
- CORMOSEA (business meeting), 2000 (Box 48, Folder 19)
- CORMOSEA collection development, 2000 (Box 48, Folder 20)
- CRL (Center for Research Libraries)-SEA (Southeast Asia) Program Task Force, 1995-1998 (Box 48, Folder 21)
- Dissertations SEAP, 1993-1999 (Box 48, Folder 22)
- Echols Collection accounting - invoices, 1992-1998 (Box 48, Folder 23)
- Echols budget, 1986-1993 (Box 48, Folder 24)
- Echols Collection Development, 1986-1995 (Box 48, Folder 25)
- Joel M. Halpern papers, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 26)
- IDC (Inter Documentation Company), 1997 (Box 48, Folder 27)
- George McT. Kahin, 1994-1997 (Box 48, Folder 28)
- Library of Congress I, 1994-1995 (Box 48, Folder 29)
- Library of Congress II, 1992-1994 (Box 48, Folder 30)
- Manuscripts and Archives, 1986-1988 (Box 48, Folder 31)
- Maps, 1994-1995 (Box 48, Folder 32)
- Palm leaf manuscripts - photographs, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 33)
- Pramoedya, 1998-1999 (Box 48, Folder 34)
- Preservation/Conservation, 1991-1996 (Box 48, Folder 35)
- Public Affairs, 1994-1999 (Box 48, Folder 36)
- Reference Question, 1991-2000 (Box 48, Folder 37)
- Requests via mail, 1990-1997 (Box 48, Folder 38)
- SEAM (Southeast Asia Microforms Project), 1995 (Box 48, Folder 39)
- SEAM, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 40)
- SEAM, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 41)
- SEAM, 2000 (Box 48, Folder 42)
- SEAP Executive Committee, 1997-1998 (Box 48, Folder 43)
- SEAP Executive Committee, 1999-2000/2001 (Box 48, Folder 44-45)
- SEAP Library, 1986-1995 (Box 48, Folder 46)
- Sidharta Project, 1997 (Box 48, Folder 47)
- Susenas, 1995 (Box 48, Folder 48)
- Visitors, 1993-2000 (Box 48, Folder 49)
- Visitors, 1993-2000 (Box 48, Folder 49)
- Philippines, 1975-1994 (Box 49, Folder 1)
- Southeast Asia, 1971-1990 (Box 49, Folder 2)
- Indochina Refugee #1, 1975-1990 (Box 49, Folder 3)
- Indochina Refugee #2, 1981-1982 (Box 49, Folder 4)
- Indochina Miscellaneous, 191978-1991 (Box 49, Folder 5)
- Laos Refugee, 1978-1988 (Box 49, Folder 6)
- Laos Miscellaneous #1, 1973 (Box 49, Folder 7)
- Laos Miscellaneous #@, 1958-1979 (Box 49, Folder 8)
- Asia and Pacific Refugee, 1982-1983 (Box 49, Folder 9)
- World, 191987-1994 (Box 49, Folder 10)
- 19 (Box 49, Folder 11)
- "Buddhism", 19-- (Box 49, Folder 12)
- Thailand #1, 1965-1993 (Box 49, Folder 13)
- 19 (Box 49, Folder 14)
- 19 (Box 49, Folder 15)
- Thailand #2, 1976-1992 (Box 49, Folder 16)
- Thailand #2. books, pamphlets, etc., 1948-1992 (Box 49, Folder 17)
- Thailand #4. Thai language, unidentifed documents, 19-- (Box 49, Folder 18)
- Vietnam, misc. booklets/pamphlets, etc. #1, 1950-1985 (Box 49, Folder 19)
- Vietnam, misc. booklets/pamphlets, etc. #2, 1955-1960 (Box 49, Folder 20)
- Vietnam, misc. booklets/pamphlets, etc. #3, 1968-1991 (Box 49, Folder 21)
- Vietnam, misc. booklets/pamphlets, etc. #4, 1950 (Box 49, Folder 22)
- Vietnam Refugee, 1981-1992 (Box 49, Folder 23)
- Vietnam and Cambodia, Conflict and US Relations, 1947-1991 (Box 49, Folder 24)
- Cambodia, 1989-1991 (Box 49, Folder 25)
- Cambodia/Kampuchea Refugee, 1976-1987 (Box 49, Folder 26)
- International School Bangkok, 1973-1975 (Box 49, Folder 27)
- crocheted doily with embroidery in woven center, Undated (Folder Mss. Box 27)
- Book Shipments to Northern Illinois University, 1971 (Box 50)
- Books to Yale, 1969-71 (Box 50)
- Book Shipments to UCLA, 1969-72 (Box 50)
- Indonesia: Microfilm Reports, 1971-75 (Box 50)
- CUL: Wason Book Count, 1968-71 (Box 50)
- CUL: Wason Book Count, 1971-75 (Box 50)
- CUL: Wason Statistics, 1971-73 (Box 50)
- Outdated Survey, 1972-73 (Box 50)
- CUL: Wason Outgoing Mail Record (out of date) (Box 50)
- Library of Congress: Hobbs, 1971 (Box 50)
- Northern Illinois University: Thai Shipment Letters (Box 50)
- Phan Thien Chau, 1964-75 (Box 50)
- Serials Dept.: Indonesia (General), 1974 (Box 50)
- Serials Dept.: Indonesian NSPS and Newsletters (Box 50)
- Malaysia, Singapore, Brunei General, 1974 (Box 50)
- Serials Dept.: Chopmen, 1970 (Box 50)
- Serials Dept.: Thailand (General) (Box 50)
- Correspondence: Vietnam, 1965-69 (Box 50)
- Correspondence: Gelinas, 1966-72 (Box 50)
- Gelinas, 1972-75 (Box 50)
- Serials Dept.: Gelinas by Date (Box 50)
- Mrs. Ta Van Tai (Box 50)
- Notice of Publications on Their Way (Box 50)
- Space Committee (Box 50)
- Statistics: Misc. (Box 50)
- Statistics: Backlog (Box 50)
- Vietnam War Veterans (Box 50)
- Title I-C Projects (Box 51)
- Notes, 1975 (Box 51)
- Wason Search Committee, 1982 (Box 51)
- Brochure, 1982 (Box 51)
- Correspondence, 1978 (Box 51)
- Newspaper Microfilming Program, 1981 (Box 51)
- Serials - NPAC Cancellations, 1981 (Box 51)
- NPAC - Serials, 1980 (Box 51)
- Exchange: Hanoi Soc. Sci., 1985 (Box 51)
- Exchange: Indonesia, 1982 (Box 51)
- Exchange: USSR / SEAP, 1982 (Box 51)
- Exchange: Xiamen, 1982 (Box 51)
- SEAP - EC Index, 1969-74 (Box 51)
- CRL, 1984 (Box 51)
- Crawford, 1986 (Box 51)
- Bowker, 1976 (Box 51)
- Asia Serials, 1982 (Box 51)
- Archives (Box 51)
- Thai (Box 51)
- SEA Research Tools (Box 51)
- SEAP Development Fund, 1983 (Box 51)
- SEAP (Box 51)
- Thai (Box 51)
- Microfilming Rates (Box 51)
- Malaysia Microfilm (Box 51)
- Technical Processes Subcommittee (Box 51)
- Microfilms (planned), 1973 (Box 51)
- Microfilms in Progress, 1975 (Box 51)
- Titles for Microfilming, 1974 (Box 51)
- SEAM / NAP Holdings, 1973 (Box 51)
- Mekong, 1973 (Box 51)
- Kho Malay Classics, 1966 (Box 51)
- Javanese Manuscripts (Box 51)
- Biographies, 1948 (Box 51)
- Correspondence, 1975 (Box 51)
- Accounting, 1976 (Box 51)
- Stationery (Box 51)
- SEA Periodizations (Box 51)
- Correspondence, 1976 (Box 51)
- Correspondence, 1976 (Box 51)
- Cormosea, 1977 (Box 51)
- Correspondence, 1976 (Box 51)
- Notes, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 51)
- Thai Notes, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 51)
- CORMOSEA(Committee on Research Materials on Southeast Asia) - Technical Services Subcommittee (Box 51)
- Letters, 1974 (Box 51)
- CORMOSEA: Coming Meeting, 1972 (Box 51)
- Javanese Romanization, 1979 (Box 51)
- CORMOSEA, 1981 (Box 51)
- AAS (Association for Asian Studies) (Box 51)
- AAS Meeting, 1970 (Box 52)
- AAS Meeting, 1978 (Box 52)
- AAS Meeting, 1979 (Box 52)
- AAS Program Committee, 1979 (Box 52)
- AAS, 1980 (Box 52)
- AAS, 1981 (Box 52)
- AAS, 1982 (Box 52)
- AAS, 1983 (Box 52)
- AAS, 1984 (Box 52)
- CORMOSEA, 1975 (Box 52)
- CORMOSEA, 1977 (Box 52)
- CONSAL, 1983 (Box 52)
- CONSAL, 1982 (Box 52)
- Development Strategies, 1985 (Box 52)
- Directories, 1976 (Box 52)
- Duplicates, 1983 (Box 52)
- Echols Collection - Notes, 1986 (Box 52)
- Echols Collection - Photographs (Box 52)
- Corson, 1986 (Box 52)
- CRL (Center for Research Libraries), 1978 (Box 52)
- CUL: Administrative Staff (meetings and memos), 1970-74 (Box 52)
- Director's Report - SEA, 1951-52 (Box 52)
- CUL, 1984 (Box 52)
- CUL Staff, 1984-85 (Box 52)
- Chapter - Draft (Box 52)
- Cole, James, 1985 (Box 52)
- Cornell Stationery (Box 52)
- Binding - Title II-C, 1981 (Box 52)
- Brochure, 1982 (Box 52)
- Budget: CUL, 1986 (Box 52)
- Canada, 1984 (Box 52)
- Annual Reports, 1984-85 (Box 52)
- Appreciation, 1982 (Box 52)
- Correspondence - Giok Po Oey, 1980 (Box 52)
- SEA Titles, 1975-78 (Box 52)
- Chinese-Malay Literature, 1961 (Box 52)
- Drafts (Box 52)
- Drafts, 1975 (Box 52)
- Wason Accessions, 1960-74 (Box 53)
- Health Care, 1986 (Box 53)
- Echols - Wason, 1985 (Box 53)
- Luce Collection, 1976 (Box 53)
- Latest, 1986 (Box 53)
- Pending, 1975 (Box 53)
- Correspondence, 1981 (Box 53)
- Anderson, 1992 (Box 53)
- Annual Report, 1983 (Box 53)
- Work Folder, 1980 (Box 53)
- Annual Statistic Report, 1980 (Box 53)
- VN Micro Project, 1986 (Box 53)
- Trips, 1972 (Box 53)
- Stationery - Stamps (Box 53)
- Title IIC Grant and Procedures, 1976 (Box 53)
- Thai Selection (Box 53)
- SEA Accessions, 1977 (Box 53)
- Southeast Asia Catalog, 1983 (Box 53)
- Supplement, 1977 (Box 53)
- Southeast Asia Program, 1970 (Box 53)
- Southeast Asia Program Budget, 1984 (Box 53)
- Staff (Box 53)
- Southeast Asia Program: Ex. Comm., 1979 (Box 53)
- Southeast Asia Program: Swank, 1973-89 (Box 53)
- Southeast Asia Program: Executive Comm., 1975 (Box 53)
- Visitors, 1983 (Box 53)
- Wason Search (Box 53)
- Chapter Correspondence, 1987 (Box 54)
- Friday Meetings (Box 54)
- Friends (Box 54)
- Don, 1986 (Box 54)
- Griswold, 1985 (Box 54)
- Hoang-Ngoc-Thanh, 1979 (Box 54)
- Hoang-Ngoc-Thanh, 1985 (Box 54)
- Thanh (Ceased), 1971 (Box 54)
- Kahin, 1973 (Box 54)
- Major Purchases, 1984 (Box 54)
- Museum Pusat, 1975 (Box 54)
- Myo Lwin, 1982 (Box 54)
- G.P. Oey, 1986 (Box 54)
- Newspapers: Thai (Box 54)
- Newspapers: Malaysia, Singapore, 1982 (Box 54)
- Newspapers: SEA (Box 54)
- Newspapers: Phillipines, 1980 (Box 54)
- Newspapers: Indonesia, 1976 (Box 54)
- NPAC, 1976 (Box 54)
- Outreach, 1977 (Box 54)
- Personnel, 1971 (Box 54)
- Personnel, 1984-85 (Box 54)
- Prices, 1985 (Box 54)
- Publishing, 1984 (Box 54)
- Purchases for the New Budget Year (up to previous year), 1977 (Box 54)
- Reimbursements, 1979 (Box 54)
- Retired Files, 1983 (Box 54)
- RLIN Searching, 1983 (Box 54)
- Romanization (Box 54)
- Serials - 102 (Box 54)
- Serials (Box 54)
- Serials - Title RC, 1980 (Box 54)
- Serials, 1977 (Box 54)
- Serials - 550, 1982 (Box 54)
- Selectors (Box 54)
- Search, 1986 (Box 54)
- Purchases for the new budget year (up to previous year), 1979 (Box 54)
- Reimbursements, 1979 (Box 54)
- Retired Files, 1983 (Box 54)
- RLIN Searching, 1983 (Box 54)
- Correspondence - Indonesia, 1984 (Box 54)
- Correspondence- Indonesia, 1984 (Box 54)
- Collection Statistics, Book Counts, 1979 (Box 54)
- Surakarta MS Project, 1978 (Box 54)
- Southeast Asia Program: Director, 1973-1984 (Box 54)
- Statistics, 1968-69 (Box 55)
- 1966 (Box 55)
- CORMOSEA - Early, 1968 (Box 55)
- 1969 (Box 55)
- Miscellaneous Info., 1972-78 (Box 55)
- 1972 (Box 55)
- CUL Weekly Gazette, 1985 (Box 55)
- Work Folder, 1980 (Box 55)
- Bernath Correspondence, 1966 (Box 55)
- Old: General Correspondence, 1971 (Box 55)
- CORMOSEA, 1968-70 (Box 55)
- Wason Collection, 1950-54 (Box 55)
- Martin, 1984-85 (Box 55)
- 1985-86 (Box 55)
- Southeast Asia Catalogues (Box 55)
- Papers, 1949-60 (Box 55)
- Malaysia (Box 55)
- Microforms, 1986 (Box 55)
- Blanket Orders, 1986 (Box 55)
- CORMOSEA - Chicago, 1972 (Box 55)
- Indonesia, 1946-49 (Box 55)
- Personnel, 1986 (Box 55)
- Exchange, 1986 (Box 55)
- Echols, 1982 (Box 55)
- Handbook Notes (Box 55)
- Acquisitions, 1986 (Box 55)
- Papers, 1947-60 (Box 55)
- Catalogs, 1973 (Box 55)
- Oral History Project (Box 55)
- AAS, 1973 (Box 55)
- Miscellaneous (Box 55)
- Letterbox, 1979 (Box 55)
- Letterbox, 1982 (Box 55)
- 1960s (Box 55)
- Miscellaneous with Guide, 1981-82 (Box 55)
- Funds: 409, 410, 1979-80 (Box 55)
- Encumbrances, 1986 (Box 55)
- Encumbrances, 1981 (Box 55)
- Abbreviations, 1986 (Box 55)
- SEAP, 1979 (Box 55)
- AARP, 1986 (Box 55)
- CUL: Wason Curator & Hiring of Diane Perushek (Box 55)
- Faculty Requests (Box 55)
- Phillipines, 1986 (Box 55)
- CUL: Finch, 1985 (Box 55)
- Echols, Nancy, 1986 (Box 55)
- Echols Operations, 1976 (Box 55)
- Echols, John M., 1973 (Box 55)
- Encumbrances, 1982 (Box 55)
- Videos
  - Pramoedya Ananta Toer at Cornell, April 1999; V-1104